# FRANCES STEPHENS

Entry Level Web Developer



francesstephens@hotmail.com



+447904938199



London, United Kingdom



frances-stephens-a05134263/



https://github.com/Frannerz

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Developing knowledge of Python

### SKILLS

Mentoring

Communication

Presenting

Team management

Operational problem-solving

Leading change

Training and Development

Self-starter

### SUMMARY

A career-changer with a passion for mathematics and computing, moving from the education sector into the world of tech. A skilled teacher and senior leader with experience of working collaboratively, problem solving, planning and leading change, overseeing teams, managing a large workload, and working in high-pressure situations. Excellent communication skills and a keen eye for detail.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Assistant Headteacher

January 2020 - Present

Arnhem Wharf Primary School, London

- Working as part of the senior leadership team to identify areas for improvement, plan for change and lead school on improvement.
- Responsible for quality of teaching and learning in Years 4, 5 and 6.
- Line managing a large team to ensure best practice.
- Designing and leading training, both in-person and online to 150+ members of staff.
- Managing a large workload, prioritizing tasks and delegating where necessary.
- Communicating effectively both in person and through written forms with various stakeholders.
- Operational management and deployment of staff.
- Working collaboratively with families and outside agencies.
- Ensuring safeguarding practices are followed to keep children safe.
- Leading on Relationships and Health Education and on Educational Visits across the school.
- Writing policies.
- Ensuring statutory guidance is followed by all members of staff.
- Reading and disseminating information about new government guidance.
- Adapting to regular changes in staffing, curriculum and policy.
- Leading on performance management for my team, and carrying out support and capability procedures if staff are underperforming.
- Managing challenging behaviour and supporting children to develop better mental wellbeing.

### Class teacher and Pupil Voice Lead

January 2015 - January 2020

Arnhem Wharf Primary School, London

- Teaching a range of age groups from 6- to 11-year-olds.
- Developing, and adapting to, an ever-evolving curriculum.
- Teaching a full range of subjects, including computing and mathematics.
- Mentoring less-experienced colleagues and student teachers.
- Managing a large workload.
- Adapting resources and making use of a range of technologies to teach effectively online during the pandemic.
- Learning new information to become an expert in the subjects that I taught, including coding (through programming languages such as Scratch).
- Building relationships with families and the wider school community.
- Regularly reflecting on and trying to improve my own practice.

# FRANCES STEPHENS

### EDUCATION

## Web Development Kickstarter Code First Girls, May 2023

Codecademy Full-Stack Engineer In process

Maths Specialist Teacher Qualification (MAST) Institute of Education 2014

Post Graduate Certificate in Education

University of East London 2009

Applied Psychology and Sociology, BA (Hons), 2:1 University of Brighton 2007

A-Levels Maths, Biology, Psychology John Roan School, 2003

GCSEs 10 grade A-C including Mathematics (A), Science (AA) and English (B) John Roan School, 2001

### INTERESTS

Exercise: CrossFit, gymnastics, swimming, pilates

Travel

Reading

Coding

Environment and sustainability

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE continued

### Teacher (contract work)

September 2013 - December 2014

Capita Education Recruitment, London

- Teaching children aged 4-11 in several different schools.
- Adapting quickly to different workplaces.
- Teaching a wide range of subjects.
- Thinking on my feet and working effectively under pressure.
- Building positive relationships with colleagues in a short space of time.
- Developing strategies to build trust quickly with children and manage challenging behaviour.

### Class Teacher and Maths Lead

September 2009 - August 2013

Invicta Primary School, London

- Teaching a full range of subjects, including computing, to children aged 9-10.
- Promoted to Maths Lead after one year of teaching.
- Leading on the teaching of maths across the school.
- Developing and leading training on maths teaching.
- Observing and mentoring other teachers in the teaching of maths.
- Developing my own subject knowledge of all subjects that I taught.
- Managing a large workload effectively.
- Analysing school, local and national data.
- Presenting school data to OFSTED inspectors and school governors.
- Leading whole-school assemblies.

References available upon request.